Bilegjargal Jargalsaikhan "Jargal"

https://bilegjargal.github.io/portfolio

Email: bjargal56@gmail.com Mobile: +1-425-295-9281 http://linkedin.com/in/bilegjargal-jargalsaikhan

SUMMARY

I am a full stack developer with both functional and object-oriented programming background. I have 3 years experience in programming enterprise system software using React.js, Node.js, and the Agile/SCRUM software development method at one of the largest software development and IT services firm in Mongolia. I am a quick problem solver, self-motivated, independent learner, and a great team player who positively challenge diverse solutions.

SKILLS

- Frameworks: Node.js, ReactJS, Angular, ExpressJS, Agile/SCRUM, Jest
- Programming: Javascript(ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, SQL, NOSQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Git, NPM, YARN, RESTful API, Ubuntu, Linux Mint

EXPERIENCE

Career Note: Completed on-campus studies and currently taking my last semester of classes in distance learning. I am available for full time employment

ITZONE COMPANY

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia, Software Developer, Sep 2016 - Jul 2018

- Working as a full-stack software developer on a business tool for contract management, using ReactJS Redux, Node.js, ExpressJS, and MongoDB, contributing to all phases of the software development process, including sprint planning, development, unit testing(JEST), iteration reviews, and deployment.
- Implemented a new function to add dynamic fields to a contract document. Resulted in a 30 percent reduction in the implementation time for new customer.
- Created a feature that generates a contract payment schedule by weekly, monthly or custom time interval with automatic invoice creation.
- Implemented CI/CD(continuous integration/continuous delivery) to my team using cucumber-Gherkin syntax. As a result our production delivery became more reliable and bug free.
- On-site client development to quickly solve many major and minor bugs. Awarded Customer Happiness Award in the first quarter of the year.

ITZONE COMPANY Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia, Software Developer-Intern, Part-time, Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

- Contributed to the development of a Supply Chain Management System and Customer Relationship Management System as part of a full ERP system. Used Javascript(ES6), C#, and Oracle SQL technology
- Created a back-end logic to compute all types of transaction flows over the finance and inventory modules, resulting in a 20 percent improvement in inventory and finance department workflows while completely eradicating faulty transactions.

EDUCATION

 Maharishi University of Management Master of Science in Computer Science; Fairfield, IOWA *Aug. 2018 – In progress*

• Mongolian University of Science and Technology Bachelor of Science in Computer Science;

Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia *Aug. 2012 – Jun. 2016*